Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
This is Acting Captain Kodai Susumu
of the space battleship Yamato.
I do not wish any further hostilities.
I request that you quietly leave this space zone.
Yamato...
That damn Yamato...
Without supplies or reinforcements,
further advancement is just...
Pursue the Yamato !
The Earth ship left us behind,
and alive, despite their victory !
We can't go on living or die without destroying it !
Even if we burn in hell for acting against
the Emperor's orders, we'll stop at nothing...
...to fight !
His Majesty wishes to see your tenacity.
Great Emperor Zorder has told you as much...
...but such human-like emotion acts as
a deadly poison to those of Gatlantis.
In fact, they began pursuing the Yamato
on their own, out of sheer hatred.
They are a "contaminated" unit, which befouls the Great Emperor's flawless army.
His Majesty wishes to eliminate...
Mr. Mill...
...I came here because I was
told I could fight the Yamato.
That's a given.
We trust that you will deal with the Yamato,
the source of the contamination.
My reason for existence is to
report what I observe to the Emperor.
Ten seconds to warp out.
Prepare to fire the Desler Cannon.
We Gatlantians prosper because we're
not controlled by individual emotion.
To be honest, it's not so scary to
get deeply involved with humanoids.
Desler Cannon, energy charge 120%.
Things can turn devastating...
...when you get tossed around by emotion or love.
Why ?!
The contaminated unit was
eliminated by Desler's fleet.
He has passed his first test.
Is it because of his gratitude to His Majesty...
...or because he's realized
he has no other place to be ?
I don't think it's that simple.
You had better watch carefully
what makes a human so human.
Anti-matter ?
No, it's similar in behavior,
but I'd rather call it unknown energy.
And it was detected in Teresa's
communication wave the other day ?
Yes. Plus an enormous amount of data that can be decoded by our technology.
Planet Telezart is surrounded
by complex gravitational waves.
Beyond that, we've detected signs
of a heavily armed defense fleet.
And here's the actual shape computed just now.
What's that ?
Telezart is encased in crustal rocks with different properties.
Therefore, it's reasonable to assume that those
were brought there from different planets afterward.
What kind of technology do they have ?
Furthermore, enemy bases have been
identified in multiple locations within those rocks.
I see.
The planet itself is hollow,
and has a high energy signature.
It's an unknown type of energy
coming from an alternate dimension.
Or, it could be...
Teresa.
If so...
Even if we are able to meet,
we won't be able to touch her.
That's...
Do you have any idea of how to save her ?
The enemy's defense seems strong,
and landing on Telezart would be difficult.
We must act swiftly by combining the Yamato's firepower and air power with the Space Marine's mobility.
Naturally, we should consider using
the wave motion gun as well.
Deputy Commander, you said the
unknown energy is decreasing.
Yes.
If those rocks surrounding Telezart are some kind of energy extraction system, it all makes sense.
Teresa's power is...
...being drained by Gatlantis.
We don't have much time.
How are you going to fight, Acting Captain ?
What brought you here ?
You think I need a reason ?
I was just thinking about what
you did to the Yamato's engine.
Why did you stay on the Yamato ?
This warmth...
Who is that ? Me ?
Enemy missiles from 4, 7, and 11 o'clock !
Anti-air combat. Activate guns.
Evasive maneuvers, engaged.
More missiles at 3 o'clock.
Are we surrounded ?
Any ships ?
None within range.
Use the attack vectors to calculate the
number of enemy ships and their coordinates.
Wave motion shield !
Concentration of missiles at 5 and 7 o'clock.
Shima, all ahead full and pull away !
This many missiles from outside our range ?
Target speed is up by 70%.
Transposition area, expanding.
Transposition paused.
Looks like that ship hasn't changed at all.
Mr. Mill, I'll let you see
something interesting, so...
...continue your work on
finding the Yamato's coordinates.
Input new coordinates into the
instantaneous transposition device.
Missiles from all directions !
An attack from ahead ?
That's impossible.
We managed to pull away.
Then, from another unit ?
That's a huge fleet !
The enemy must know the Yamato's coordinates.
Incoming missiles from nearly all directions !
We're completely surrounded !
Acting Captain, status !
Calculating an escape route !
Calculation complete.
In 18 seconds there will be a six
second opening in the direction of 1:16.
It could be a trap.
Coordinates will be unstable at the warp exit.
Shima !
Steady !
Wave motion engine, maximum output.
Emergency warp.
Warp !
The target has entered warp.
Such a marginal window of opportunity...
It still finds a way out of deadly situations.
That's the Yamato.
Warp complete.
No contact on radar or scanners.
Hey, this is...
Yeah, very familiar.
We fell between dimensions.
Pops, the wave motion factors
have been excessive since we arrived !
The energy conversion rate is rising rapidly !
What ?
Is the pressure damper malfunctioning ?
Check it !
No, that's not it.
Chief, please shut down the engine.
What ?
At this rate, the Yamato will...
Stop the engine.
Stopping the engine.
Remains of a super nova ?
This space is filled with it.
These elemental particle reactions are caused by the high energy of accelerated electrons and protons.
The wave motion engine
limitlessly takes in energy from space.
If it continues the energy conversion...
...the Yamato will be destroyed
by an internal explosion.
Are we drifting inside an
ammunition depot, so to speak ?
Enemy contact ?
I can't confirm.
The enemy can use their radar ?
Chief, the sub engine should work.
Got it.
Nanbu, load the aft torpedo tubes !
Fire diversionary torpedoes
on the Acting Captain's mark !
Roger.
Shima, evasive maneuvers.
Turn starboard.
Fire !
Internal engine pressure
rising at an accelerated pace.
Lascaux class ships are
experiencing this as well.
Bombardment is risky.
Let them continue.
Impressive.
Your trick seems to nullify both
distance and spatial obstacles.
That's what the cosmo wave is.
Thanks to that, I haven't had
any trouble finding the Yamato...
...so far.
A high-dimensional communication using telepathy...
I believe that's what Teresa's
prayer is called. Am I right ?
They can attack normally in this space ?
Why don't you respond ?
What is this ?
Enemy fire is missing the Yamato.
Internal explosion due to
excessive energy conversion.
Like Emperor Zorder,
you're unique as a Gatlantis person.
As is the spy, who is aboard the Yamato.
That tubular planetary body is...
...clearly artificial.
Of an unknown species again ?
No, the style is similar to Archelian design.
If it is an Archelias design, we have
a good chance of making use of it.
It's still a gamble, though...
Veer the Yamato into the tubular planetary body.
That must be the core of this space.
Having a problem using
your cosmo wave, I presume ?
Since your proud trick no longer works, let me
try something a little more conventional, Mr. Mill.
What will you do ?
We'll use our eyes to search.
It's no use.
Your telepathy won't reach the Great Emperor.
Feels like we've entered a sausage tube.
This planetary tube's dimensional hierarchy
appears to be different from that of the outside.
Is that even possible ?
So, the two spaces are fused seamlessly.
Deputy Commander, if that's the case,
can we get back to normal space ?
Yes, but...
Gatlantis's unique philosophy and all
its technology is simply impressive.
However...
...which of the Emperor's
subordinates truly understand him ?
They may be the source
of contamination to your people...
...but they could also be poisonous liquor with a mesmerizing aroma, or a favorite toy.
The Emperor probably doesn't
wish to destroy the Yamato.
The Yamato and its crew must be a source
of amusement he hasn't had in some time.
The Emperor knew from the beginning
that the Yamato means nothing to me.
I'll keep this gun, Mr. Mill.
Release the wave motion energy in this space, which will then
create a radiant heat that the wave motion engine can take it in.
Induction of radiation.
Use this hollow structure to warp ?
One mistake and the ship will explode.
It's like using an explosive
to jump start the engine.
The Chief and I will each
have to shoulder half the responsibility.
No, everyone will...
...bear the responsibility.
We can't waste time in a place like this.
You planned this all along.
You lured it in here to cut off our telepathy.
I am a man who never forgets humiliation.
You know the consequence
of using that in a place like this.
It will light up this space...
...as well as the Yamato and the
fleet the Emperor entrusted to me.
Desler !
Watch carefully.
It's your job, isn't it ?
Extra dimensional implosion detected.
Why ?
The approaching wave motion energy is colliding with this space to create a shock wave.
Kodai, release the gravitational
anchor and ride the shock wave !
The Yamato should be able to
warp without the wave motion engine !
Roger.
Shima, can you ride the wave ?
Reflectivity inside the tube is unstable.
I'll aim for the center of radiation.
Radiant induction wave approaching.
Inertial canceler to maximum !
It's made contact aft, and it's pushing us.
Open all intake valves.
All hands, prepare for warp.
Three...
...two...
...one...
Warp !
The Yamato jumped.
Incredible luck as always.
We did it.
Without the core, this alternative space will vanish soon.
What're you doing ?
Mr. Mill, aren't you happy to regain your
cosmo wave, now that this space has collapsed ?
Fuhrer, the entire army has
been awaiting your return.
I appreciate your continuous
loyalty from the bottom of my heart.
Heil Desler.
That's my real fleet.
The Great Emperor will eventually become aware of it.
So, don't rush.
Won't you accept ?
We were caught in an enemy trap.
I simply repaid my debt.
But Kodai...
The Acting Captain believes you're
the right person to be the Captain.
“Everyone will bear...” Is that it ?
When it comes to his own situation...
I understand your concern,
but the wall Kodai's facing right now...
He has to break through it himself.
If he appears to fall, you give him support.
Your parents were helping each other.
You can do that, too.
That's how humans have always lived.
Right.
The data from earlier...
We warped with an energy
three times greater than normal.
What caused the collapse of that alternate space ?
There are some abnormal neutron
behaviors in the radiant implosion.
That must be...
...the Desler Cannon.
Episode 11
Challenge from Desler !
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Analyzer:
Kamo Kimihiko:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Cho
Sunseki Kazuhiro
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Togire yuku manazashi wa
Your fading gaze turns to...
Hijikata Ryu:
Katsurai Touko:
Desler:
Keyman:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Mill:
Genitz:
Maser:
Cosmodart:
Gadel Talan:
Gamiroid:
Ishizuka Unsho
Kaida Yuko
Yamadera Koichi
Kamiya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Uchiyama Koki
Umetsu Hideyuki
Kiyama Shigeo
Kawai Toshiya
Yakamura Kotaro
Yano Masaaki
...Yuuja no tashika na rashinban
...a trusted compass of a warrior
Yakusoku wa nai mama ni...
Without any promise...
...Yatsura mo ikari wo agedasu
...they will weigh anchor in response
Kowarekaketa kono sekai wa...
The half-destroyed world has named...
...Te wo sashinoberu hito no na wo
...the people who can lend a hand
Namari iro no kotae ga...
A lead-colored response...
...Kurayami ni tsumetaku tsukihanasu
...cut coldly through the darkness
Inochi wo tsumuide tokoshie no tami
Spin the thread of life for the everlasting journey
Kibou no kuni e
To the nation of hope
Otoko no sadame ni seigi tsuranuki
Stay faithful to justice in men's destiny
Torawareta ashita wo sukuu no sa
Save the besieged future
Shuuen ni mukaeba itsuka rifujin na sekai ga
When the end comes near, the unexpected world will...
...Kurenai no sakazuki de otagai no yuuki tataeyou
...cheer both sides with a crimson cup
Hakai to souzou densetsu no kake...
Destruction and creation, and legendary wagers...
...Yatsura mo onaji sa
...fall onto both sides
Tatakai no hibuta
The outbreak of war
Towa ni kirarete honou no okite
It repeats endlessly in a destined blaze
Kodoku to shouri ga korogariochiru...
Loneliness and victory will eventually be known...
...Mekuru meku uchuu no hate made
...throughout dazzling space
Preview
I've grown tired of seeing it.
The White Comet vanished !
Do you...like him ?
Kodai, she's made a move !
Could that be...
...Gatlantis's home ?
Are you going to kill me ?
Now, get ready to warp !
Episode 12
Astonishing White Comet Empire ? Yamato Breaks Free !